翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
As a test of our deep understanding of arrays,
为了测试我们对数组理解的深入程度
let's talk about two-dimensional arrays in Java now.
让我们讨论一下 Java 中的二维数组
So we're not going to be using these in class for a little while,
我们暂时不会在课堂上使用这些东西
but just to get acquainted with them, let's check them out today.
不过为了熟悉一下，来看一看
So here I'm going to have a bunch of code--
我这里有一堆代码
which I'm just going to jump straight to the Visualizer on this one--
这次直接跳到 visualizer
which is going to allow us to create arrays of array references.
这允许我们创建数组引用的数组
So the syntax in Java for making what in other languages--
Java 中的语法来制作其他语言中的...
well, what you might call a two-dimensional array is as follows.
可能称之为二维数组
When I do int bracket, int square braces, square braces,
执行 int[][] 时
what it's saying is make for me an array of integer array references.
为我创建一个整型数组引用的数组
So here we got one box.
这里得到一个盒子
And it's allowed to store a reference to a list of inter array references.
它允许存储数组引用的数组的引用
So let's see an example here.
来看一个例子
So when I say pascalsTriangle equals new int 4,
执行 pascalsTrangle = new int[4][]
what that's going to do is going to create an array of int array references.
这将创建一个整型数组引用的数组
Each of these is allowed to point at an array.
其中的每一项都允许指向一个数组
An array of what?
什么数组？
Of integers.
整型数组
And this right here is a 64-bit address of this array of array references.
这里是这个数组引用数组的64位地址
Getting a little, but don't worry.
别担心
Now just as we could anytime, we could create a variable of the type of these boxes.
我们可以创建这些盒子类型的变量
So what's the type of each of these boxes?
这些盒子都是什么类型的呢？
Int array references.
整型数组引用
So I can make a new such variable and assign it equal, and copy of the bits.
所以我可以创建一个新的变量，并复制这些位
There you go.
这样
We'll have a more interesting example down here.
下面会有一个更有趣的例子
Next up, we could say, you know what?
接下来
I'm tired of this being null.
我厌倦了这一切都是 null
In fact, I want to point it at an int array,
实际上我想把它指向一个整型数组
because that's what it's for it.
这就是它的意义
This is an array of looking at int arrays.
这是一个查看整型数组的数组
So what we're going to do is create here an array of size 1,
所以我们要创建一个大小为1的数组
which contains a value 1, and point this at--
它包含值1，并指向它
the Visualizer does that for us.
visualizer 展示了
So next up, we say, OK, you know what?
接下来
I'm tired of this being null.
我厌倦了这一切都是 null
So I'm going to make a new array of 2, size 2, and point this at it.
我要创建一个大小为2的数，然后指向它
Kind of a funny way of drawing this, but there you go.
画的方式有点奇怪，但就这样
Now we say OK, same deal.
同样
We're going to repeat this and create two more int arrays and point our pointers at it.
重复这个过程，再创建两个整型数组，并将指针指向它
So actually if you are visualizing this stuff later,
实际上，如果你以后再使用 visualizer
for your reference there is an option,
这有个选项供参考
same one we had before which prefers non-nesting layouts, where we get box and pointer diagrams.
与以前一样，它倾向非嵌套布局，可以得到框图和指针图
It also makes us have vertical layouts.
还提供垂直布局
So if we rerun that, now we get what might be a little to read.
重新运行，现在得到的东西更易读
Next up, we have rowTwo.
接下来我们有 rowTwo
This line, what it does is, it creates a box of 64 bits that can store a reference to an int array, one of these.
这行的作用是，它创建了一个64位的盒子，可以存储整型数组的引用
And then we point that at pascalsTriangle2.
然后将其指向 pascalsTriangle[2]
So what do we do?
该怎么做呢？
We copy the bits.
复制这些位
What are the bits?
位是什么？
This arrow.
这个箭头
So in other words, rowTwo points at this.
换句话说，rowTwo 指向这里
So what's interesting about this is that we could actually modify our original pascalsTriangle object, up here, using this rowTwo reference.
有趣的是，我们可以使用这个 rowTwo 引用修改原来的 pascalsTriangle 对象
So in your mind, you might think of it as OK, well, it's like a sequence of arrays.
在你脑海里，把它想象成一个数组序列
And it's called pascalsTriangle.
这就是 pascalsTriangle
I can actually get a hook inside the middle of it.
实际上，我可以在它中间弄一个钩子
I'm just going right into the belly of that pascalsTriangle.
直奔 pascalsTriangle 的腹部
And I can, for example, say rowTwo, item 1 is now minus 5.
举个例子，令 rowTwo 的第1项为-5
So be aware that's possible because they're all the same.
要知道这是可能的，因为它们都一样
Alternate ways to instantiate an array,
这是数组实例化的替代方式
well, we've seen this one already.
我们已经看过了
So if we say matrix equals-- actually, I'm going to go to the non-vertical layout for this part.
matrix = ...改一下非垂直布局
I'm going to go back--
我要回去了
So one way to create one of these array of arrays is the syntax we had before.
创建数组中的数组一种方法是我们之前使用的语法
So that does just what we saw before.
这就是我们之前看到的
It creates an array of array references.
创建数组引用的数组
But Java actually also allows us to specify a number here.
但是 Java 实际上也允许我们在这里指定一个数字
So what this number means is, you know what, I don't want just a bunch of empty array references.
这个数字的意思是，我不想要一堆空的数组引用
I want you to, Java, create for me a bunch of default arrays of size 4.
我希望 Java 为我创建一组大小为4的默认数组
They will all get the default value for the type here.
在这里 它们都将获得该类型的默认值
So in other words, this new matrix declaration
换句话说，这个新的矩阵声明
is going to not create just the array of int references,
不仅会创建整型引用数组
but also the actual integer arrays.
还会创建实际整型数组
So this creates, you can think of it as, if we look at this carefully,
所以这就产生了...仔细看一下
this line that we're about to run, it creates one array.
运行这行代码，它创建了1个数组
This line actually creates five arrays.
这行实际上创建了5个数组
This array, plus this, this, this, and this.
这个数组，还有这些
So five total arrays are created-- one of references, four of integers.
总共创建了5个数组，1个引用数组，4个整型数组
And if you want to create a literal array,
如果你想要创建字面量数组
if you decide that you don't want to have this obviously very wordy way of declaring pascalsTriangle,
不想使用这种非常冗长的方式来声明 pascalsTriangle
there is a literal notation for doing two-dimensional arrays.
有一种创建二维数组的字面量表示法
So in that case, we would just get the same thing laid out a little differently for some reason.
这种情况下会得到几乎相同的布局
So that is the heart of what makes a two-dimensional array.
这就是构造二维数组的核心
They are actually references of references.
它们实际上是引用的引用
So you may find that's a little hard to fully grok.
你可能会发现这有点难理解
But it will be OK, because later when we do this assignment called Seam Carving,
没事，稍后我们做这个叫 Seam Carving 的作业
you will get better hand.
你会掌握得更好
And these are just repeating some points that I said during the earlier demo.
这些只是重复了之前提到的一些观点
So this very first line, it creates one box of 64 bits that refers to an array of int arrays-- int array references.
第一行创建了一个64位的盒子，指向整型数组引用的数组
See, confounding.
看，令人困惑
This next line though, it in this case, creates four additional boxes and each of them is null.
下一行创建了4个额外的盒子，每个都是 null
So this is one box, four boxes.
这是1个盒子，这是4个盒子
Down here if we look at this line just to pick out what it does total,
看看这行做了什么
well, it first creates an array which has three boxes.
它首先创建一个有3个盒子的数组
It puts the numbers 1, 2, and 1 in them.
将数字1、2和1放入其中
And then it assigns the address to this box.
然后将地址分配给这个盒子
And as as all said before, this one makes one total array.
正如之前所说，这是个总的数组
This is five arrays.
这是5个数组
So just some highlights of terminology that maybe are not that interesting to listen to me say,
这只是一些重点术语，也许听我说这些术语并不那么有趣
but you can convince yourself of the truth of these statements.
但你可以说服自己相信这些说法的真实性
So now an exercise for you that I'd like you to ponder.
现在做一个练习，思考一下
Knowing what we've just said,
记住我们刚才说的话
because just watching me do that is probably not going to lead to a great deal of understanding,
仅仅看着我这么做可能不会带来太多的理解
I want you to tell me here when I run this code
我想让你在我运行这段代码的时候告诉我
and create these other variables,
创建这些其他变量
what is going to be the value of x, 0, 0 and w, 0, 0 when this code completes?
代码完成时 x[0][0] 和 w[0][0] 的值是多少？
And in this case, what I want to have you do is click on this Answer link if you want the answer.
如果你想知道答案，点击这个答案链接
And if you really hate going to a web site, opening the slides, and clicking the link, I put it up top
如果你真的讨厌打开幻灯片并点击链接去网站，那么我把它放在上面
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
so you can type it in manually.
这样你就可以手动输入了